<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/journal</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/journal"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2014-10-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>From Concept to Code - Built in 12 Hours</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/journal/Built-in-12-Hours/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/journal/Built-in-12-Hours/</id>
    <published>2014-10-14T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-14T23:05:27-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You probably don’t realize this, but this is a new website. I designed and built it in approximately 12 hours. Last night I initialized a new github repo around 7PM. Tonight I’m writing this post at 10:30PM. While this period is over 24HRS, I’m talking actual time spent working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t the first time I’ve built a personal website in a short time. I find personal websites can often turn into a long-drawn out process with too much time spent diddling around. Because of this I’ve set out to design and build a lot of my personal sites in a short timeframe. I find it allows me to make decisions and move forward without second guessing myself. Most importantly, I’m able to ship something of quality and not bog myself down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, when I set out to rework my site I wanted to add a blog. I talk about wanting to write more &lt;a href="http://imandrewcohen.com/journal/I-Want-to-Write/"&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;, and offline. However, I’ve always been afraid I have nothing worth saying. After a few conversations at Brooklyn Beta last week, I knew this wasn’t the case. I needed to start already. To add more fuel to the fire my first design-centric blog post, &lt;a href="http://robots.thoughtbot.com/animating-with-keynote"&gt;Prototyping Animations in Keynote&lt;/a&gt;, was published on thoughtbot’s blog yesterday. Turns out it was well received more than I could ever imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a quick sketch or two, nothing really of note, I set out to build this site. I went straight from pen and paper to code. I decided it was best to host my own solution with a simple static-site generator, &lt;a href="http://middlemanapp.com"&gt;Middleman&lt;/a&gt;. SASS is the pre-processor of choice with thoughtbot’s suite of tools, &lt;a href="http://bourbon.io"&gt;Bourbon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://neat.bourbon.io"&gt;Neat&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://bitters.bourbon.io"&gt;Bitters&lt;/a&gt; as the obvious choice. Lastly, I moved over to &lt;a href="http://pages.github.io"&gt;github pages&lt;/a&gt; for my hosting purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My site is far from done, but after 12 hours of work it’s in a great place. In a short time I was able to take an idea and ship this website. I designed and built a solid foundation for me to iterate on. Most importantly I built a home for my writing to live.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Prototyping Animations in Keynote</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/journal/Prototyping-Animations-in-Keynote/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/journal/Prototyping-Animations-in-Keynote/</id>
    <published>2014-10-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-14T23:58:11-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One look on Dribbble, and you’ll notice the abundance of animations that emphasize interaction. The increasing number of devices, screens, and use cases have required designers to think of new ways to improve the usability of applications. Animation can be a tool for solving these problems. A simple effect can help a user transition between screens, and understand a cohesive experience across an ecosystem of devices. A well-designed animation guides users to the most crucial areas of the product, and is just plain delightful!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have always found myself envious of those who are able to bring life to their interfaces in After Effects. The detail and delight made me wish I could harness the clunky interface, but it never worked out for me. Recently, there has been an influx of applications that focus on being simplified tools that allow us to get the job done. Programs like Sketch, Pixate, Invision, and Flinto are a few examples. We’re no longer stuck having to use the sledgehammer when a ball-peen hammer is needed. We can choose the tools that fit our workflow best and allow us to get tasks done faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Really Keynote?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings me to my new favorite animation program, Keynote. Yes Keynote, the prettier Apple version of PowerPoint. Keynote has been spoken about in the past as a great tool for creating wireframes and prototypes, but not much for animation. I love Keynote because it’s fast, free, easy to learn, and it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Ohh Pretty" src="http://images.thoughtbot.com/animating-in-keynote/system-select.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently Andrew Haskin of Frog Design recreated &lt;a href="http://designmind.frogdesign.com/blog/google-s-material-design-video-recreated-in-keynote.html"&gt;Google’s Material Design Video in Keynote&lt;/a&gt;. I was impressed with his ability to recreate complex animations in what seemed like a very simple program. Using his Keynote file as a guideline, I dug in to the mechanics and mastered animating in Keynote in roughly an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Keep it Simple&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Animation and motion can be very daunting. Many designers have a background that has made us very familiar with static layouts. For those first approaching animation, it’s easy to get overwhelmed. The most basic tool in your belt is the most powerful one, your pen. Start simple by sketching out ideas around your beginning state, your end state, and how you think content should animate in a logical fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is easy to go overboard with animation — think about the Flash days. Remember animation is a tool to create a seamless experience, not the experience itself. Look for ways you can guide users’ eyes to key interaction points or showcase the most important aspects of the interface. In the end, don’t overcomplicate to make things pretty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Get Set Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So your animation is planned, and you’re ready to push pixels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fire up Keynote and create a blank slideshow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the top right, select the document tab and change your slide size to the appropriate canvas necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change your presentation type to be self-playing and remove the delays on transitions and builds. This will make sure everything flows seamlessly between slides.
&lt;img alt="Document Tab" src="http://images.thoughtbot.com/animating-in-keynote/document-tab.png" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After that, make sure the Build Order palette is open, which can be found at view &amp;gt; show build order. Alongside the Animate palette, the build order palette is where you’ll spend the bulk of your time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hold on one second, though! Before you can animate, you need to export your assets from your program of choice. Anything that you plan to move around independently of other objects needs to be a slice. Keep in mind that sometimes it is easier to build your element inside of Keynote.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once you have your assets, drag them into Keynote and rebuild your layout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Lets Animate Something Basic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you’re ready to animate and should have a good idea of what you’re trying to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the first object you want animated and head to the Animate palette in the top right. Keynote was created for slideshows, so the palette will reflect that with three options. When hunting down a specific effect, I find it helps to think of my animation as three key steps: building in (fade in), do something (action), building out (fade out).
&lt;img alt="Animate Tab" src="http://images.thoughtbot.com/animating-in-keynote/animate-tab.png" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select Add an Effect and find the desired animation you’re looking for. Tweak your effect by selecting the duration you want, the acceleration, and other options. Once done, click add effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The effect shows up in your build order palette, which is the order animations are triggered at.
&lt;img alt="Build Order" src="http://images.thoughtbot.com/animating-in-keynote/build-order.png" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select an effect in the build order palette. You can make it so the effect triggers at the same time or after the one before it. This allows you to chain together multiple animations in one slide. If you want something a little more drastic, let’s talk Magic Move.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Magic Move&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magic Move is probably the most effective and well&amp;hellip; magical thing about animating in Keynote. It is a transition effect that animates objects from one slide to their positions on the next. It will then fill the gaps on the things you want by moving, fading, scaling, etc. So let’s give it a whirl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take the slide you currently have and duplicate it. One of the slides will exist as the first state and the second as the final state. You want to make sure the objects you want to change exist in both slides.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go back to the first slide, select the animate tab, click add a transition, and select magic move.
&lt;img alt="Magic Move" src="http://images.thoughtbot.com/animating-in-keynote/magic-move.png" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the properties as you see fit, but leave “Move by object” as is. Also, make sure start transition automatically is selected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now go to the second slide and move your objects around as you see fit. If you want something to fade in, (inserted comma) change the opacity from 0 to 100. If you want it to move, change the position to where you want it to end up. Magic move will take care of the rest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preview your animation by selecting Preview on the first slide in the Animate tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tweak and refine until you’ve figured out the exact animation you’re looking for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Combine Them&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you’ve done basic animation effects on a single slide and played with magic move by combining two slides, you can move into animating your entire experience. There are tons of ways to build animations in Keynote, and there is no wrong way to do it. A great rule of thumb, is to try and link as many animations for a single screen in the build order palette. Then, when it comes to an entirely new screen, you create a new slide and continue from there. Magic Move is a great solution for a large amount of the transitions out there, but it is easy to go overboard. Fine tuning each step of the animation through build order and timing offers the most control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Closing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’re done, you can easily export your animation to a Quicktime .mov for sharing. In the end, it’s all about experimenting and seeing what works for you. Keynote wasn’t built for prototyping animation, so at times you’ll see some shortcomings, but overall it’s simple, powerful, and fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I’ve attached an animation I recently did for our client, &lt;a href="https://www.martialcodex.com"&gt;Martial Codex&lt;/a&gt;. Keynote has helped me convey the animations to our developers as we design and build out the Android app. Take a look, mess with my file, and you’ll quickly see it’s not that hard to get rolling in Keynote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/qk7ku7s0fnrkkbm/MartialCodex-system-select.zip?dl=0"&gt;Download Martial Codex Animation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally Published on &lt;a href="http://robots.thoughtbot.com/animating-with-keynote"&gt;Giant Robots Smashing into Other Giant Robots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ramblings on Getting Older</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/journal/Ramblings-On-Getting-Older/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/journal/Ramblings-On-Getting-Older/</id>
    <published>2014-08-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-14T23:50:21-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been doing a lot of thinking about getting older. Nothing concrete, but more-so reflecting on where I am in life. I’m 2.5 months into my marriage and just turned 29. I know that doesn’t seem old, but events around me have had me thinking more about life. It’s not a quarter life crisis, just me reflecting, being thankful, and scared at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My grandmother is in a bad state of health. People die, but she’s a woman I never thought would. After my grandfather passed away 10 years ago she just kept moving along. While she had bad periods she never seemed to deteriate, until recently. The other day I found myself reflecting on my summers spent at their beach house, sailing with my grandfather, catching crabs, surfing, and just enjoying life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems so long ago I was doing this, in fact 12+ years since I was there. In this time I’ve had so many experiences, good and bad. Twelve years is a long time and a lot can happen then, but it seems just like yesterday my grandfather passed away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that time I’ve graduated high school, moved to Washington DC, raced mountain bikes all over the United States, attended and graduated college, found my calling in digital design, visited multiple countries, run my own successful business, been engaged, rescued my dog, been unengaged, made and lost friends, moved to Colorado, helped design a cutting-edge product, been engaged, bought a house, joined a leading consultancy in our field, married my best friend, and a million other things in between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure my list could go on for days and days, but my point being is that I’ve done so much in 12 years that I shouldn’t be afraid of the future, but I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve found myself feeling a bit of unease. We’ve been talking about having kids in the next few years, our plans for the future, our finances, and generally things that aren’t that easy to discuss. I know there are tons of great and scary things ahead for me, but I guess that’s what makes life a journey. My thoughts have taken my emotions everywhere, and even writing this has been tough. Reality is I am a lucky man, and I should be, scratch that, I am thankful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally Published on &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@andrewcohen/ramblings-on-getting-older-b52d9b1ed84b"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I Want to Write</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/journal/I-Want-to-Write/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/journal/I-Want-to-Write/</id>
    <published>2014-05-12T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-13T22:41:54-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking this for weeks, months, years. It’s something I know is important in my career field as a designer. It’s something that is important as a human being. It’s something that I should do more of. Writing is a creative endeavor that has always alluded me. I’ve never had a successful blog. Successful in the sense that it lasted more than a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing is a skill that I’ve never truly felt 100% comfortable with.
You’ll quickly pick up that I’m not the greatest writer in the world, and I know that. I’ve known it since my 7th grade English teacher said “Andrew is not the best writer, but he’s enthusiastic.” Enthusiasm can only get you so far. You need to practice, write, write some more, and just execute. I tell myself the problem is that I just never know what to write about, or the fact I think I’m just not good at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is writing is hard for everyone.
OK, not everyone, but for a large part of the population. For some people it is their creative skill, craft, and passion. To me it has always been something I hated. If I do something I want to be the best I can be at it. Unfortunately the best I can be at writing has always been pretty mediocre. Reality is that I’ve never truly made a concerted effort to get better at it. Practice does make perfect, but for starters you have to actually practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I consistently read articles about being a better writer, or how writing 1000 words a day is fantastic exercise for creatives. I love the idea of it, but it has always just been an idea to me. I’m passionate about a lot of things in my life. From design to cycling and everything in between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel I have tons of interests I could write about, I’m just not sure what I’ll write about.
The reality is that shouldn’t matter. Sometimes I fear it’s me being afraid of others judging, which is strange as that’s never stopped me in other aspects of life. I mean I’m a designer for christ’s sake. My work has been critiqued by peers, denied by clients, and used by plenty. I make my living in one of the most public facing fields so others seeing another “thing” of mine shouldn’t be a big deal right? Wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end fear might be my biggest road block.
However, I can’t let that stop me. You need to get past numerous hurdles in life to grow and become better. I’ve decided that today I stop with the excuses. I stop thinking that I can’t get better. I make a list of the topics and ideas that I should write about. I realize that fear is pointless. I get past this hurdle I’ve had for the longest time. Most of all I start writing and stop being lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally Published on &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@andrewcohen/i-want-to-write-79b573c9a729"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
